Guide to the Civil War Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Civil War manuscripts collection
1836-1960
1861-1865
MS 619
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16.5
(33 boxes and 1 folio)
The Civil War Manuscripts Collection was created to give the researcher more direct access to small and fragmentary collections of material on the subject of the Civil War in the United States, 1861-1865. It is an intentionally assembled collection of diaries, correspondence, photographs, printed material, and ephemera primarily documenting military events and daily camp life, as well as family life on the home front and civilian activities. Many Connecticut regiments are represented throughout the collection.
General note
Further additions to this collection will meet departmental standards for additions to artificial collections and thus not amount to more than .25 linear feet of material or contain material in smaller quantities which warrant collection level status due to individual or subject content. Additions will include material generated during the Civil War period, 1861-1865, or the reminiscences, remembrances and recollections of individuals who were a party to events relating to the war.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Civil War Manuscripts Collection was created to give the researcher more direct access to small and fragmentary collections of material on the subject of the Civil War in the United States, 1861-1865. It is an intentionally assembled collection of diaries, correspondence, photographs, printed material, and ephemera primarily documenting military events and daily camp life, as well as family life on the home front and civilian activities. Many Connecticut regiments are represented throughout the collection.
Accruals
Further additions to this collection will meet departmental standards for additions to artificial collections and thus not amount to more than .25 linear feet of material or contain material in smaller quantities which warrant collection level status due to individual or subject content. Additions will include material generated during the Civil War period, 1861-1865, or the reminiscences, remembrances and recollections of individuals who were a party to events relating to the war.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: I. Civil War collections, 1836-1960. II. Civil War manuscripts, 1861-1902.
Peninsular Campaign, 1862; Confederate States of America; New Haven (Conn.) -- History; New York (State) -- History, Military; Richmond (Va.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns and battles; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Medical and sanitary affairs; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Miscellanea; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Pictorial works; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Prisoners and prisons; Baldwin, Neilson Abeel, 1839-1906; Bartlett, Charles Griswold, 1848-1912; Beebe, Lydia T.; Blaisdell, Betsy A.; Blaisdell, Hiram; Blaisdell, Melino; Blaisdell, Roxanna; Blaisdell, William; Briggs, Henry S. (Henry Shaw), 1824-1887; Carpenter, Arthur B.; Dana, Charles A. (Charles Anderson), 1819-1897; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889; Eldridge, Milo D.; Foote, Merrill; Forbes, Ira Emory, 1843-1911; Gay, John O.; Gile, David Herrick, 1836-1898; Hancock, Celenda; Hubbard, Robert, 1826-1898; Humphreys, A. A. (Andrew Atkinson), 1810-1883; Ingalls, Truman, 1804-1867; Ingalls, William Henry Harrison, 1841-; James, Edward Christopher, 1841-1901; Jarvis, George Cyprian, 1834-1901; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Lusk, William Thompson, 1838-1897; Morgan, Edwin D. (Edwin Denison), 1811-1883; Norman, William F.; Paddock, Elbridge E.; Parmalee, Henry Spencer, 1843-1902; Porter, Thomas W.; Press, A. A.; Rhodes, William Barnard, 1807-1878; Seymour, Thomas D. (Thomas Day), 1848-1907; Shaler, Alexander, 1827-1911; Sharpe, George H. (George Henry), 1828-1900; Warren, William Henry, 1852-1926; Waters, Albertus Aretius; Willard, Lovell F., 1832-1864; Winder, John H. (John Henry), 1800-1865; Blaisdell family; Giles family; Gill family; Ingalls family
- Civil War collections, 1836-1960; 1836-1865; Series I
  Arrangement
  Material is arranged alphabetically be personal name, family name, or subject.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Civil War collections, consists of materials centered around or collected by a specific person or family, primarily in the form of copious correspondence and diaries. Battles and Leaders of the Civil War, a six volume work of letters, documents, and photographs, is included in this series.
  - Baldwin, Neilson Abeel (1839-1906)
    Contains correspondence (originals and typed copies), 1862-1865, printed materials, photographs, and memorabilia.
    - Correspondence, 1862 November 1-1865 October 14, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Printed material and memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (duplicates of typed copies) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bartlett, Charles Griswold (1848-1912)
    Consists of seven typed manuscripts signed, autograph manuscript signed and articles on various Civil War battles.
    - "Chancellorsville," "Battle of Antietam", Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Fredericksburg," "Battle of Gettysburg", Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Peninsular Campaign", Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Pope's Campaign", Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Valor", Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Battles and Leaders of the Civil War, edited by Robert Underwood Johnson and Clarence Clough Buel of Century Magazine
    This work was extended from four to six volumes by the insertion of three hundred portraits and one hundred autograph letters and documents. Letters and documents include the correspondent's name, the type of document, the date of the document and the page number within the volume.
    - Volume 1
      - Lincoln, Abraham (1809-1865), letter signed, p. viii, 1860 October 19 (Box 3)
      - Scott, Winfield (1786-1866), autograph letter signed, p. 12, 1854 March 14 (Box 3)
      - Buchanan, James (1791-1868), autograph letter signed, p. 18, 1857 February 17 (Box 3)
      - Davis, Jefferson (1808-1889), autograph letter signed, p. 100, 1855 July 11 (Box 3)
      - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton (1812-1883), autograph letter signed, p. 102, 1868 February 13 (Box 3)
      - Memminger, Christopher Gustavus (1803-1888), autograph letter signed, p. 108, 1879 October 25 (Box 3)
      - Dix, John Adams (1798-1879), autograph letter signed, p. 148, 1871 February 15 (Box 3)
      - Cameron, Simon (1799-1889), autograph letter signed, p. 168, 1860 April 11 (Box 3)
      - McDowell, Irvin (1818-1885), letter signed, p. 170, 1846 September 25 (Box 3)
      - Patterson, Robert (1792-1881), autograph letter signed, p. 172, 1869 April 15 (Box 3)
      - Baldwin, John Brown (1820-1873), autograph letter signed, p. 260, 1870 April 25 (Box 3)
      - Thomas, Lorenzo (1805-1875), letter signed, p. 384, 1844 October 29 (Box 3)
      - Zollicoffer, Felix Kirk (1812-1862), autograph letter signed, p. 388, 1846 August 21 (Box 3)
      - Buckner, Simon Bolivar (1823-1914), autograph letter signed, p. 418, 1883 June 6 (Box 3)
      - Pillow, Gideon Johnson (1807-1878), autograph letter signed, p. 426, 1874 December 18 (Box 3)
      - Larned, B. F., autograph letter signed, p. 428, 1836 December 6 (Box 3)
      - Hamilton, Schuyler (1822-1903), autograph letter signed, p. 462, 1886 January 13 (Box 3)
    - Volume 2
      - Grant, Ulysses Simpson (1822-1885), autograph letter signed, p. 488, 1864 December 10 (Box 3)
      - Force, Manning Ferguson (1824-1899), autograph letter signed, p. 516, 1892 February 8 (Box 3)
      - Nelson, William (1824-1862), autograph letter signed, p. 524, Undated (Box 3)
      - Sherman, Thomas West (1813-1879), autograph document signed, p. 672, 1840 January 20 (Box 3)
      - Cullum, George Washington (1809-1892), autograph letter signed, p. 674, 1872 June 19 (Box 3)
      - Porter, David Dixon (1813-1891), autograph letter signed, p. 22, 1865 June 6 (Box 3)
      - Butler, Benjamin Franklin (1818-1893), autograph letter signed, p. 54, 1858 October 20 (Box 3)
      - Bailey, Theodorus (1805-1877), autograph letter signed, p. 92, 1868 January 25 (Box 3)
      - Seward, William Henry (1801-1872), autograph letter signed, p. 114, 1841 December 22 (Box 3)
      - Sumner, Charles (1811-1874), autograph letter signed, p. 132, 1853 October 12 (Box 3)
      - McClellan, George Brinton (1826-1885), autograph letter signed, p. 160, 1882 [May ?] 22 (Box 3)
      - Stanton, Edwin McMasters (1814-1869), document signed, p. 162, 1864 January 23 (Box 3)
      - Slocum, Henry Warner (1827-1894), autograph letter signed, p. 182, 1867 June 28 (Box 3)
      - Barry, William Farquhar (1819-1879), autograph letter signed, p. 200, 1874 November 13 (Box 3)
      - Rains, Gabriel Jones (1803-1881), document signed, p. 230, 1844 April 13 (Box 3)
      - Howard, Oliver Otis (1830-1909), autograph letter signed, p. 252, 1881 October 21 (Box 3)
    - Volume 3
      - Porter, Fitz-John (1822-1901), autograph letter signed, p. 330, 1869 February 5 (Box 4)
      - Franklin, William Buel (1823-1903), autograph letter signed, p. 376, 1880 March 4 (Box 4)
      - Hunt, Henry Jackson (1819-1889), autograph letter signed, p. 408, 1885 July 30 (Box 4)
      - Pope, John (1822-1892), autograph letter signed, p. 450, 1867 February 3 (Box 4)
      - Sigel, Franz (1824-1902), autograph letter signed, p. 470, 1862 April 19 (Box 4)
      - Sykes, George (1822-1880), autograph letter signed, p. 482, 1864 March 1 (Box 4)
      - Longstreet, James (1821-1904), autograph letter signed, p. 526, 1871 January 11 (Box 4)
      - Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss (1816-1894), autograph letter signed, p. 540, 1856 November 7 (Box 4)
      - Hayes, Rutherford Birchard (1822-1893), autograph note signed, p. 590, 1880 March 15 (Box 4)
      - McLaws, Lafayette (1821-1897), autograph letter signed, p. 594, 1869 February 24 (Box 4)
      - Cobb, Howell (1815-1868), autograph letter signed, p. 596, 1848 March 6 (Box 4)
      - Johnson, Bradley Tyler (1829-1903), autograph letter signed, p. 614, 1888 August 20 (Box 4)
      - Patrick, Marsena Rudolph (1811-1888), autograph letter signed, p. 638, 1869 August 10 (Box 4)
      - Lee, Robert Edward (1807-1870), letter signed, p. 662, 1869 May 5 (Box 4)
      - Hitchcock, Ethan Allan (1835-1909), autograph letter signed, p. 696, 1865 November 28 (Box 4)
      - Buell, Don Carlos (1818-1898), autograph letter signed, p. 700, 1844 August 17 (Box 4)
      - Ducat, Arthur Charles (1830 -1896), autograph letter signed, p. 746, 1875 January 23 (Box 4)
    - Volume 4
      - Kirby-Smith, Edmund (1824-1893), autograph letter signed, p. 12, 1884 March 2 (Box 4)
      - Gilbert, Charles Champion (1822-1903), autograph letter signed, p. 52, 1898 March 9 (Box 4)
      - Carter, Samuel Powhatan (1819-1891), autograph letter signed, p. 62, 1891 April 23 (Box 4)
      - Burnside, Ambrose Everett (1824-1881), autograph letter signed, p. 108, 1866 December 29 (Box 4)
      - Meagher, Thomas Francis (1823-1867), autograph letter signed, p. 110, 1885 October 26 (Box 4)
      - Hooker, Joseph (1814-1879), document signed, p. 160, 1848 July 10 (Box 4)
      - Jackson, Thomas Jonathan "Stonewall" (1824-1863), document signed, p. 204, 1848 July 10 (Box 4)
      - Cochrane, John (1813-1898), autograph letter signed, p. 216, 1879 June 8 (Box 4)
      - Chase, Salmon Portland (1808-1873), autograph letter signed, p. 240, 1868 August 24 (Box 4)
      - Butterfield, Daniel (1831-1901), autograph letter signed, p. 242, 1889 May 12 (Box 4)
      - Meade, George Gordon (1815-1872), autograph letter signed, p. 256, 1861 March 4 (Box 4)
      - Hampton, Wade (1818-1902), autograph letter signed, p. 270, 1889 May 5 (Box 4)
      - Doubleday, Abner (1819-1893), autograph letter signed, p. 278, 1888 September 3 (Box 4)
      - Hancock, Winfield Scott (1824-1886), autograph letter signed, p. 286, 1883 January 30 (Box 4)
      - Sickles, Daniel Edgar (1825-1914), autograph letter signed, p. 296, Undated (Box 4)
      - Chamberlain, Joshua Lawrence (1828-1914), autograph letter signed, p. 314, 1883 February 17 (Box 4)
      - Garnett, Richard Brooke (1819-1863), autograph letter signed, p. 346, 1847 January 18 (Box 4)
      - Bingham, John Armor (1815-1900), autograph letter signed, p. 372, 1872 February 29 (Box 4)
      - Lee, Stephen Dill (1833-1908), autograph letter signed, p. 466, 1866 July 24 (Box 4)
    - Volume 5
      - Pemberton, John Clifford (1814-1881), autograph letter signed, p. 544, 1870 September 25 (Box 5)
      - Taylor, Richard (1826-1879), autograph letter signed, p. 590, 1866 December 26 (Box 5)
      - Augur, Christopher Columbus (1821-1898), autograph letter signed, p. 592, 1877 May 14 (Box 5)
      - Bragg, Braxton (1817-1876), autograph letter signed, p. 600, 1867 November 18 (Box 5)
      - Johnson, Richard W. (1827-1897), autograph letter signed, p. 618, 1880 April 15 (Box 5)
      - Hardee, William Joseph (1815-1873), document signed, p. 622, 1848 February 15 (Box 5)
      - Rosecrans, William Starke (1819-1898), autograph letter signed, p. 626, 1885 February 4 (Box 5)
      - Walthall, Edward Cary (1831-1898), autograph letter signed, p. 654, 1879 July 11 (Box 5)
      - Dana, Charles Anderson (1819-1897), autograph letter signed, p. 714, 1888 May 24 (Box 5)
      - Beauregard, Pierre Gustave Toutant (1818-1893), letter signed, p. 2 (in volume 4 originally), 1866 April 4 (Box 5)
      - Welles, Gideon (1802-1878), letter signed, p. 40, 1865 April 18 (Box 5)
      - Meigs, Montgomery Cunningham (1816-1892), letter signed, p. 106, 1864 January 14 (Box 5)
      - Barnard, John Gross (1815-1882), autograph letter signed, p. 114, 1869 August 21 (Box 5)
      - Rodenbough, Theophilus Francis (1838-1912), autograph letter signed, p. 188, 1870 September 18 (Box 5)
      - Hawley, Joseph Roswell (1826-1905), autograph letter signed, p. 208, 1877 March 27 (Box 5)
      - Johnston, Joseph Eggleston (1807-1891), autograph letter signed, p. 260, 1866 February 16 (Box 5)
    - Volume 6
      - Harrison, Benjamin (1833-1901), autograph note signed, p. 300, 1885 January 6 (Box 5)
      - Polk, Leonidas (1806-1864), autograph note signed, p. 308, 1864 January 9 (Box 5)
      - Corse, John Murry (1835-1893), autograph letter signed, p. 322, 1871 May 4 (Box 5)
      - Hood, John Bell (1831-1879), autograph letter signed, p. 326, 1866 June 20 (Box 5)
      - Smith, Thomas Kilby (1820-1887), autograph letter signed, p. 350, 1866 June 4 (Box 5)
      - Marmaduke, John Sappington (1833-1887), autograph letter signed, p. 374, 1865 July 20 (Box 5)
      - Farragut, David Glasgow (1801-1870), document signed, p. 378, 1864 March 26 (Box 5)
      - Smith, William Sooy (1830-1916), autograph letter signed, p. 416, 1864 January 3 (Box 5)
      - Early, Jubal Anderson (1816-1894), autograph letter signed, p. 492, 1883 March 21 (Box 5)
      - Sheridan, Philip Henry (1831-1888), autograph letter signed, p. 506, 1869 July 14 (Box 5)
      - Preble, George Henry (1816-1885), autograph letter signed, p. 594, 1871 November 2 (Box 5)
      - Barron, Samuel (1809-1888), autograph letter signed, p. 596, 1880 March 8 (Box 5)
      - Sherman, William Tecumsah (1820-1891), autograph letter signed, p. 662, 1879 August 26 (Box 5)
      - Wilson, James Harrison (1837-1925), autograph letter signed, p. 758, 1888 October 15 (Box 5)
  - Blaisdell family
    Consists of 109 items. 52 autograph letters signed from Hiram Blaisdell to his wife, Betsy, regarding his military life and services as a private in Battery A, 3rd New York Artillery; also 49 autograph letters signed from Betsy to Hiram concerning conditions at home [Martville, Cayuga County, New York]; also 8 autograph letters signed from various other members of the Blaisdell family, including William and Melino Blaisdell (Hiram's brothers), Celenda Hancock (Betsy's aunt), Lydia T. Beebe (Hiram's aunt), Roxanna Blaisdell (Hiram's sister), and Milo D. Eldridge (relation unknown).
    Hiram Blaisdell entered the 3rd New York Artillery at Auburn, New York, in September 1864; a month later he was sent to New Bern, North Carolina, where he remained almost the whole of his one year term of enlistment. An unusually homesick soldier, Hiram filled his letters with poignant regrets that he could not be at his wife's side and with much sober advice on how she was to conduct their farm during his absence. Aside from complaining of the hardships and dullness of camp life, Hiram made few observations on the war, except to anticipate a rapid peace and his return home. He does, however, give some news as to the number of rebels deserting to the Union lines.
    The dull routine of camp life is broken twice--in February (1865), Hiram went on a raid and the following month (March) he participated in the hotly contested battle at Kinston, North Carolina. [Note: he gives a very good description of the effectiveness of artillery against the Confederates.] Shortly after the Battle of Kinston, Hiram succumbs to diarrhea and spends the rest of his enlistment in the LeNoir General Hospital.
    Betsy's letters give a very detailed picture of life for those back home in Martville, Cayuga County, New York. She describes the hardships and loneliness of a childless wife on an isolated farm; the terrible snowstorms of upstate New York; the lack of funds and difficulty of bringing in crops; lack of help from neighbors, etc.
    - Betsy Blaisdell to Hiram Blaisdell, 1864 October-1865 May (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
    - Hiram Blaisdell to Betsy Blaisdell, 1864 September-1865 Jun, undated (Box 6, Folder 7-14)
    - Blaisdell family (miscellaneous), 1864-1865 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Carpenter, Arthur B.
    Arthur B. Carpenter served as a sergeant and later as an officer in the Union Army, 19th Infantry Regiment during the Civil War. The letters, mainly to his parents in Monson, Massachusetts, give war news, battle descriptions, comments on army life and politics, camp routine, civilians with whom he came in contact, military leaders, politics, religion, Negro emancipation, and details of the contemporary scene, as well as descriptions of the countryside through which he passed.
    - Arrival at Indianapolis, starting in business and foreboding of war, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Engraving of North Western Christian University on letter; impressions of Hoosiers; local reactions toward Civil War, 1861 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Photo of Arthur B. Carpenter as a sergeant (signed); Battle of Pittsburgh Landing (Shiloh Church, Tennessee); problems with guerillas; skirmishes along picket lines; Confederate evacuation of Corinth, Mississippi; description of convalescent barracks; honorable discharge as sergeant; commission as second lieutenant, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Account of five-day battle around Stone River near Murfreesboro, Tennessee, 1863 January-April (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Charge on Confederates at Hoover's Gap near Tullahoma, Tennessee; skirmishes on the march and "restless activity" around Murfreesboro, Tennessee, 1863 May-August (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Driving Confederates toward Chattanooga, Tennessee; Battle of Chickamauga, Georgia; retreat to Chattanooga, 1863 September-December (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Establishment of National Cemetery by General G. H. Thomas; problems of supply; skirmish on Tunnel Hill, Tennessee; Battle of Resaca, Georgia; account of action at Kennesaw Mountain, Georgia, 1864 January-June (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - March on and occupation of Atlanta, Georgia; fighting along railroads and in trenches; descriptions of Confederate fortifications; notes on Sherman's drive through the South, 1864 July-December (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Routine and problems of recruiting officers; promotion to captain by Brevet; signature of Secretary of War Edwin M. Stanton; comments on Copperheads and War with Mexico, 1865-1866 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut Infantry. 9th Regiment
    Consists of 4 manuscript record books of Company E of the 9th Connecticut Infantry.
    - Order book, 1861-1863 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Morning reports, 1861 November-1863 October (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Clothing books, 1861-1864 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Dana, Charles A. (1819-1897): Recollections of the Civil War; with the leaders at Washington and in the field in the sixties; by Charles Anderson Dana, New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1898, xiii, 296 p. front. (port) 21 1/2 cm. Bound in are 12 autograph letters and numerous engraved portraits of prominent Americans. (Box 9)
    - Boutwell, George Sewel (1818-1905). Letter signed to Isaac S. Stewart [Special Treasury Agent] approving his request for a thirty day leave of absence. 1 page, Washington, DC, facing p. 12., 1872 July 3 (Box 9)
    - Dana, Charles Anderson (1819-1897). Autograph letter signed to Edwin Denison Morgan supporting Merrill Foote's request for a commission as a second lieutenant "in one of the new [NY] regiments of volunteers." At time of writing Foote was a member of Company D, 51st NY Regiment. 2 pages, New York City, following title page., 1862 August 20 (Box 9)
    - Fremont, John Charles (1813-1890). Autograph letter signed to an unidentified correspondent requesting his Washington, DC address. 1 page, New York City, facing page 7., 1889 November 25 (Box 9)
    - Hammond, William Alexander (1828-1900). Autograph letter signed to Messrs. Bullock and Crenshaw (Philadelphia druggists) ordering "100 Crusts of Vaccine Virus." 1 page, Washington, DC, facing page 74., 1862 December 13 (Box 9)
    - Hazen, William Babcock (1830-1887). Signature cut from letter. No place, facing p. 122., Undated (Box 9)
    - Hovey, Alvin Peterson (1821-1891). Autograph letter signed to John Collett acknowledging receipt of Collett's "annual report of Indiana Statistics and Geology." 1 page, folio, Mt. Vernon, Indiana, facing p. 216., 1880 December 4 (Box 9)
    - Janes, Paul. Letter signed to "Mr. Hazeltine" enclosing a copy of George W. Ross's speech before the Canadian Club of New York. 1 page, folio, New York City, facing p. 262., 1900 May 25 (Box 9)
    - King, John Lyle. Autograph letter signed (incomplete) to John Alexander Logan recommending William H. Burkhart for a federal judgeship in the Eastern District of Texas. Note by Logan on verso. 1 page, folio, no place, facing p. 96., Undated (Box 9)
    - Mayer, Brantz (1809-1879). Autograph letter signed to unidentified general promising to send a private report relative to the transfer of army headquarters from Omaha to Council Bluffs, Iowa. 1 page, Lincoln, Nebraska, facing p. 67., 1873 September 8 (Box 9)
    - Stanton, Edwin McMasters (1814-1869). Signature cut from letter, no place, facing p. 22., Undated (Box 9)
    - Welles, Gideon (1802-1878). Autograph letter signed to Andrew Johnson requesting his signature for the naval commission of William L. Low. 1 page, Washington, DC, facing p. 171., 1867 March 13 (Box 9)
    - Wilson, James Harrison (1837-1925). Autograph letter signed to Messrs. Winslow and Wilson of New York City complaining about the fact that some of his personal mail was mistakenly sent to the wrong party. 1 page, St. Louis, Missouri, facing p. 62., 1874 August 29 (Box 9)
  - Forbes, Ira Emory
    Consists of original, typed and photostatic copies of diary from time in Andersonville Military Prison.
    - Diary, autograph manuscript signed, 1864 January-December (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Diary (typed copy), 1864 January-December (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
    - Diary (photostat) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Gay, John O.